<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-03T20:01:36+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Linux</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/15/linux.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux" /><published>2020-06-15T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/15/linux</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/15/linux.html">&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I’m going to discuss Linux Environment and a simple overview of it. Also, what career opportunities are there in the Industry for Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔴 What is Linux?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux is a group of free and open-source operating systems. It’s based on core software called the Linux Kernel. The Kernel is free and open-source, which means that anyone can use it to create their version of Linux. Linux is the best-known and most-used open-source operating system. As an operating system, Linux is software that sits underneath all of the other software on a computer, receiving requests from those programs and relaying these requests to the computer’s hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔴 Why Choose Linux Over Windows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔰 Open Source
The main difference between Windows and Linux is the ladder is open-source software, whereas the code for Windows is highly secure. Since Linux is an open-source operating system, anyone with a desktop and internet access can download it, change it, and contribute to the internal Kernel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔰 Free
Another major benefit of Linux is that it’s free. Users won’t have to pay up to $250 to get their hands on a copy of a Linux distro (such as Ubuntu, Fedora).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔰 Reliable
Linux is considered more reliable than Windows. Linux offers a top-notch interface, built-in security, and unmatched uptime. Its popular competitor, Windows, is known to be sluggish at times. Users need to re-install Windows after encountering crashes or slowdowns on your system. As a Linux user, you won’t have to worry about re-installing your system to experience a faster and smoother operation. Linux helps your system run smoothly for a more extended period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔰 Secure
While no operating system is entirely risk-free, Windows is a frequent victim for developers of viruses and malware. Since there’s little that Microsoft can do about this issue, users must install an antivirus application and firewall software. Unfortunately, this eats into your memory and CPU usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux by nature is more secure than Windows. When you choose Linux as your operating system, you just need to stick to the repositories and avoid using Adobe’s Flash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔰 Privacy
With increased government monitoring and corporate collection of user data, privacy has been the number one concern for savvy internet users. Independent security experts favor Linux over Windows or MacOS. Since most Linux distributions don’t collect your personal data, you can remain somewhat hidden from Big Brother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔴 Career options in Linux&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔰 Systems administrator: The professional is responsible to manage important services like HTTP, FTP, Cron jobs, DNS, creating backups, and other server related tasks. He is also the one who looks after the security and firewall related settings in the organization. The server-oriented distributions upon which the work is generally done include Red Hat Enterprises, Debian, CentOS, and Ubuntu.
Application and Web programmer: A major part of web content related publishing business is run on Linux, PHP, Apache, MySQL, and therefore the programmers who can write code in multiple languages or are able to design different databases and applications are preferred over the conventional ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔰 Technician Job: The professional is responsible to handle workstations and desktops. The crucial areas include an understanding of partitioning, installation, providing services, troubleshooting networks, managing users, basic scripting, and operating system related problems. Getting a practical exposure in this domain is also quite easy as schools, colleges, and organizations often have requirements for candidates possessing this skillset. Getting an experience here will open a pathway for you to become an efficient Linux administrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔰 Support: You can also be among those organizations that are looking to extend support to all the professionals globally who are currently working on Linux. With the extensive growth of Linux in enterprise and corporate areas, firms choose Linux over licensed windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔰 Teaching and Writing: This is one other domain where you can see yourself employed. The above-mentioned aspirants need tutors to learn this course and you can be one of them. You can choose to do this privately or in any school, college, or any other institution. Writing can be related to providing documentation for large companies and the ones related to technical papers. You can also choose to work as a freelancer in teaching or writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔴 Job opportunities/positions in linux&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔹 DevOps Engineer
🔹 Java Developer
🔹 Software Engineer
🔹 Systems Administrator
🔹 Systems Engineer
🔹 Senior Software Engineer
🔹 Python Developer
🔹 Network Engineer
🔹 Software Developer
🔹 Linux Engineering Admin
🔹 Software Developer
🔹 Linux Engineer
🔹 TechOps Engineer
🔹 Senior Java Developer
🔹 Build release management Engineer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔴 Conclusion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here it is the current scenario and overview of career opportunities in Linux. I hope you guys get your own views on this and hit me up on the comment section.
I am always looking for different opportunities and challenges to make my personality and workflow better. I feel very grateful that we’ve a platform to make our profiles stand out.
It’s a catastrophe that even after knowing its benefits people still prefeerf windows over it. But someday we’ all will witness the revolution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kirtiwardhan</name></author><summary type="html">In this blog post, I’m going to discuss Linux Environment and a simple overview of it. Also, what career opportunities are there in the Industry for Linux.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Openmindd</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/15/openmindd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Openmindd" /><published>2020-06-15T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-06-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/15/openmindd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/15/openmindd.html">&lt;p&gt;Open source is a term that originally referred to open source software (OSS). Open source software is code that is designed to be publicly accessible — anyone can see, modify, and distribute the code as they see fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open source work sharpens your skills in ways you never realized were dull — from writing cleaner, more maintainable code to learning how to communicate well and work as a team. It’s also the best possible resume builder for a working or aspiring professional developer; potential employers can hit your repository and see what you’re capable of, and developers you’ve worked with on community projects may want to bring you in on paying gigs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, working on open source projects — yours or others’ — means personal growth, because you’re working on something larger than yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, the people who want to contribute in any project and develop, test, modify open source software product come together in a community that is open source community. A loosely organized, ad-hoc community of contributors from all over the world who share an interest in meeting a common need, ranging from minor projects to huge developments, and carry it out using a high-performance collaborative development environment, allowing the organizational scheme and processes to emerge over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps , we have build an open source community — OPEN MINDD. Everyone is free to join this community and contribute as leader, owner, maintainer, contributor, user, community member, etc. Feel free to choose your role. The community is one of the things that can make or break an open source project, and having a strong, vibrant, and diverse open source community is important to the project’s success. All of the people in the roles listed above are part of this community along with people filling other critical roles in the project for documentation, marketing, user support, and so much more. Showcase your talent and build networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having trouble with your website, project, blog or need more people to work with you in your project? Join the community and seek help. Even if you have a new idea you can make your own group and work as it takes a community to create a healthy open source project. This community is a platform that helps everyone it may be related to technical or non-technical aspects. Gain more knowledge, improve your skills, improve your logic, and implement what you have in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has a chance to make a difference. People from all backgrounds with diverse perspectives can participate. We value your opinion and ideas and we are giving you the platform to show them. In our community you will learn to collaborate, to listen to others, to embrace diversity, can make you a better person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn how to contribute, why it’s important to devote internal developer resources to participation, and why it’s important to create a strategy for open source participation and management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow us on :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linkedin : https://www.linkedin.com/company/open-mindd/
GitHub: https://github.com/open-mindd&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sabeen</name></author><summary type="html">Open source is a term that originally referred to open source software (OSS). Open source software is code that is designed to be publicly accessible — anyone can see, modify, and distribute the code as they see fit.</summary></entry></feed>